did she go base one Russell every note
mr. Russo like Sam Kim people were
biting up from the Idaho deduction
visual themselves to the cleaners
business leaders and members of the
Italian community both locally and
excellent because that you know paper
roll three leadership positions matches
and telling your decision but basil
might say I want to make sure the family
moments when we fish as a great decision
so the Gabriella is coming up Gabriella
[Applause]
so they have two Italian to come up your
dough to make this little bit longer so
I'm just before half an hour Gabrielle
mystcraft knowledge can be envisioned
hey I'm Joe Rosalina and Gary to
Gabriella so she has hated looking and
seeing as well since we've been together
for about 27 years now so almost be
together for three decades and basil
family and for 20 years now working
alongside him and a law firm when the
research disease intervention one of the
rebuild about women a national hall of
fame and we read that established to
recognize open vigils who have made a
valuable and lasting contribution to our
multicultural city and region and who
inspired the generations leaders if
you've ever heard paper which will speak
or heard others speak about table were
so there are three common themes that
you will more likely have heard one of
his dedication to the state his family
and his heritage with respect to its
failure as are no place is safe as the
bed on which is built his life he
probably practices to save him at the
christening every attempt to be a better
person for us its family I've always
said that I thought I had the greatest
dad in the world a number of amplified
have the greatest father long as well
basil truly puts his family ahead of
everything and above all houses were
endlessly which his wife my moma pack
great love it along the world as well to
create early a one
for loving and having families his
heritage one has to say before the
seasoning I really thought that that
basil it was the only person that really
cared about its heritage more than
anyone I've ever seen like I was proven
wrong this evening up today is still
great congratulations to everybody here
when you see what he has done for his
family and what he did for a law firm
for years and the hundreds of thousands
of people that he's served over that
time I just couldn't think that there
would be time for anything else yet been
alluded to he gives the national
president of the Italian sunken garden
America special enforcement are one of
the largest referral organizations in
the country he's also the president of
the defendant forum Bar Association
group group of Italian American lawyers
and judges I here in Northeast Ohio my
wife got real and I have been a part of
for the better part 25 as well any
emphasis on board of directors at night
the National County American Foundation
another very successful and large
organization that preserves and promotes
the Italian heritage so in today's world
a hero a lot of our leaders speak of
similar values and ideals the difference
that I find basil Russo's that he lives
at life in accordance with that set of
ideals and values it's really believing
this commitment to them
certainly something that we find
inspiring that inspires us to become
better attorneys but I think most
importantly and I know my wife grief it
he's really inspired us to be better
parents work for kids better partners to
each other and better people in our in
our community my I retain to shake you
only try and do as many as I can world I
haven't yet beautiful energy every color
suspected my father had to share people
be having another she serves as a
decoration sits out before the prom yeah
they surely to everything together and
experience all aspects of their life
union is the pipe out of Education to
the people of Northeast Ohio as i wake
up at all judge aware and for
contribution to the catholic diocese and
to the Italian community locally
nationally and was written to his family
I'm proud of my husband and I are
children isolated and what happening on
their families we're all proud in
question and the cream on all of being
essentially a good article do and that
he deeply
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
this is literally an excited for those
of us city has a diet I want to offer my
congratulations to each one of these
exceptional award recipients I have the
honor to be placed in such an important
company it's easy and where the sheriff
is lots of you in a few moments that are
very important to you but everything I
will say pales in comparison to the
importance and significance that my
family has in my life I feel extremely
fortunate to have been married to a very
special woman for nearly 50 years
together with the bus with for
Exceptional Children and 12 wonderful
grandchildren I'm often given credit for
the accomplishments of our children but
in fact my wife attend a much greater
impact and the final product I have
excelling in our values the importance
of education my wife early i sacrificed
her career I work to put me from college
and law school she chose to be a
stay-at-home mom at a time when many
ones were locally made to feel
inadequate because they placed child
rearing over the perceiver career my
wife again college at age 40 the same
here my son soon she became editor of
the ursuline college literary magazine
and she graduated magna laude
no one ultra didn't motivate my children
they all have to work very hard to keep
their Braves competitive with their
mothers and so my lovely wife I say
thank you for a lifetime I will not have
changed what minimal those of the
developed world on China know that there
is always wonderful children in the
family to gladly assumes the
responsibility of taking care of mom and
dad today have you met artists my
daughter Camille and my son-in-law joke
they always be there when my on TV now
I'd like to take a few minutes to share
some personal thoughts with you teach of
us in this room has been blessed with
our own ethnicity race and religion I've
always believed it is an important part
of what makes us unique and define each
of us in a very special way 7 in too
many places in our world today we find
differences in races ethnicities and
religions as being looked upon as
something which should divide people
something which should cause people to
be intolerant of one another and
something that causes conflict among
people how many wars throughout history
have been fought because people were of
different religions different races or
different ethnicities too many people in
America today often look upon our
differences that something that causes
us to be suspicious of others something
that causes us to miss trust one another
but our country and our collective
American heritage
sales for something that is much more
noble and righteous we are a nation that
prices & values diversity we have built
our entire country upon our differences
America is the greatest country in the
world because it's had a benefit of
being able to pick and choose the very
best from each of the wonderful cultures
that have been brought to our country by
immigrants and throughout the world
people of different backgrounds kampala
share the common goal of seeking a
better life for their families and
through hard work and sacrifice each of
our roots as may need the contributions
to America that we can all be rightfully
proud I believe each of us has a
responsibility to preserve our
respective Heritage's and to highlight a
contribution each of our separate groups
have made to our country I also believe
in further have a responsibility to
respect each other's contributions and
to learn from one another I've spent a
good portion my life working to preserve
the heritage customs and values my
grandparents and other Italian
immigrants brought with them to America
to keep that hair of July on my children
is ranchos I hear you that at its core
is built upon supportive and loving
families a strong work ethic and at the
bowing to our Catholic faith I take
pride in celebrating who i am and pain
you're set to my ancestors and help to
depart you just as I am sure each of you
celebrate your heritage
and never forget those has provided it
to you and for the evening today it's
becoming fashionable in certain segments
of our society for people to promote the
idea that there should be no such thing
as hyphenated American they from upon
the use of the terms african-american
Latino American korean american italian
american or any other type of therapy
they actually we should all just you
referred to as American of course in the
context that they excel sheets to the
Bible to them but next time you hear
that I'm gonna be advocated remember
what we are being asked to do is to be
with an important part of who we are the
part of ourselves that makes us
different the private ourselves that
makes us unique the part of ourselves
that makes us special I believe you
should never let anyone rob us of any
part of what makes us a person has
created and intended each of us to be
and so I think this wonderful committee
for creating and maintaining this
exceptional program that allows all of
eastern Ohio to both celebrate and share
the university that has made our
community so vibrant and so excited and
I thank all of you for celebrating our
communities diversity with us to see you
thank you
[Applause]
one last comment I believe I forgot to
make mention of the members of the
Italian sons and daughters that came out
this evening there are a hundred and
twenty-five people here
[Music]
[Applause]
that whether he whispered or district
council individually in a parking lot
Rosalie did he try to see a normal
person tonight you want to help i
greatly appreciate and support i greatly
appreciate the poison extended be over
the years and that you accept me again
this evening my heart
[Applause]